《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
APOLLO: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我感觉我在放弃我的职责
I feel like I'm abandoning my post.
是时候打包了  少  你明白我的意思
It's time to pack it in, Saul. You know it.
超过半数的船员下去新卡布里卡了
TIGH: More than half the crew's down on New Caprica already.
这里真的没有太多东西需要我做了
I'm not really doing too much up here anymore.
祝你好运
Good luck.
噢  天呀  是赛昂舰队!  他们发现我们了
Oh, my Gods. It's the Cylon Fleet. They found us.
你们也该知道这次任务只能以一种方式结束
There's only one way that this mission ends,
那就是从新卡布里卡
and that's with the successful rescue
成功营救我们的人民
of our people off of New Caprica.
你把他们都带回来了  少
You brought them home, Saul.
不是所有人
Not all of them.
我们怎么办?
What about us?
不会再有我们两个字了  行不?
There is no "us," all right?
这里已经什么都没有了
There is nothing here.
你明白没有?  什么都没有
Do you get that? Nothing!
李  你准备何时给自己找个女友?
Lee, when are you gonna get yourself a girl?
我会的  谢谢
I'm doing fine, thank you.
你还是没和小杜搞上  对吗?
You're not still frakking Dualla, are you?
我以与你共事为荣  中尉
I am proud to serve with you, Lieutenant,
也以你为我的妻子为荣
and to call you my wife.
我现在处在不同的立场
STARBUCK: I'm in a different place now.
我只想狠扁一个人 而那人最好是你
I just want to hurt someone, and it might as well be you.
上将?
DUALLA: Admiral?
Admiral?
长官 工程师需要更多的时间再次升级导航系统
Sir, Engineering is requesting more time for the nav upgrade again.
维护系统 飞行系统 武器系统
Maintenance, flight ops, weapons.
到处都是乱糟糟的 一堆事都没按时完成
We're seeing botched drills, missed deadlines across the board.
与此同时 一半机组人员都在船舱里
Meanwhile, half the crew's belowdecks.
你是想说这一场景不对劲吧?
Are you telling me something's wrong with this picture?
长官 我建议取消今晚的活动
Sir, I suggest we cancel tonight.
让所有人都回到岗位上
Call everyone back to duty.
不 不
No, no.
他们需要这个 或许我们都需要
The crew needs this. Maybe we all need it.
稍微放松一下再专心工作
Adjust our heads a little bit, refocus.
你也是 小杜 把工作放一放
You do, too, Dee. Go put your tags in.
我们会补回来的
We'll catch up.
是 长官
Sir.
这正是我想要的
That was exactly what I needed.
很高兴我的服务能让您满意
Glad to be of service.
他们让你什么时候回卡布里卡?
When do they need you back on the Caprica?
为什么 已经想要我死了?
Why? Itching to get rid of me already?
我是这个意思吗?
Did I say anything like that?
当然不是
You didn't have to.
山姆 这是我现在能做的一切了
Look, Sam, this is pretty much all that I can handle right now.
该死的
Damn it.
找这个吗?
Looking for this?
是的
Yeah.
卡拉
Kara,
我知道你经历了一场噩梦 我也能体谅
I know you went through hell on that rock and I was very patient.
我想要你做个真正的你
But I want you back.
我想要我们的婚姻回来 我的意思是真正的婚姻
I want our marriage back, I want a real marriage.
那如果我还没有准备好去面对呢?
And what if I'm just not ready for that?
我不知道 那我猜你可能永远做不到的
I don't know, then I guess it'll never be.
也许  毕竟我不是你真正要的人
Maybe 'cause I'm not what you really want after all.
如果这是你的真实想法
If that's how you really feel,
我不会试图改变它
I'm not gonna try and change your mind.
不会
I'm not.
我舞会迟到了
I'm late for the dance.
别忘了你靠在门口的靴子  山米
Don't forget your boots on the way out, Sammy.
你行的   李!   加油
KAT: You can fight them, Lee, come on!
看不出阿格森很能打嘛
If it isn't the fighting Agathon.
星芭  你又和往常一样迟到
Starbuck, late to the party as usual.
至少我及时看到你教训空军指挥官了
At least I got here in time to watch you kick the CAG's ass.
打得不错 小心右路
KAT: You got it, slick him right up.
他打得很凶  我会利用这点
He's a tough little frakker, I'll give him that.
他在戏弄我 似乎以为胜券在握
He's playing me like he's got it in for me.
知道吗 那是他的弱点
STARBUCK: You know what? That's his weakness.
当他出击时 他的右路有空档
When he charges in, he drops his right.
好了  开始
Okay? Okay. All right.
你行的 卡尔 加油
You can do this, Karl. Come on.
不错  几个月以前
Not bad. Couple of months ago,
你根本没法叫他上拳击台的
you would've had to roll him into this ring.
对 不再如此了
Well, not anymore.
如果头脑冷静的话 他还有机会
You know, with a cooler head, he might have had a chance.
加油
Come on!
一…
TIGH: One,
二…
two,
三…
three,
四…
four,
五…
five,
六…
six,
七
seven.
嘿  嘿  好了 看着我
Hey, hey, hey. All right, look at me.
你赢了 宝贝
You did it, baby.
费希尔 费希尔 你上了
Fischer. Fischer, you're up.
打得不错
You did fine.
被这样打就让你吃不消了  对吧?
Bit off a little more than you could chew, huh?
噢  拜托  李  别那样
Come on, Lee. Don't be that way.
别走啊 晚会才开始
Stick around, the night's young.
哦 那你玩好 我得失陪了
Well, I guess then you'll just have to enjoy it without me.
你干嘛不跟安德斯来
Why don't you track down Anders?
他总是笑容可掬
He's always good for a laugh.
哦 甜蜜的麻烦
Oh, trouble in paradise.
为什么我一点也不觉得奇怪呢
Now why doesn't that surprise me?
或许你已经发现我们在同一个兵营里
Yeah, well, maybe if you had found us both a billet
我们没在不同的船上
we wouldn't be living on different ships, huh?
我不相信
I don't believe this.
你在为了你该死的婚姻责备我吗?
You're blaming me for your frakked up marriage?
难道不是摆脱过去重新开始的好开端吗
Didn't really help it off to a good start, now, did you?
现在你到底想要怎么样?
Now, just how far do you want to push this?
嗯
Hmm?
这样如何?
How about this far?
现在是谁会吃不消呢  上尉?
Now who's biting off more than they can chew, Captain?
不会是我被打倒  少校
Not me from where I'm standing, Major.
让开
Excuse me.
他看上去不错
He's looking good.
真高兴他体重减轻了
I'm glad he lost the weight.
我也是
Yeah, so am I.
再见
Bye.
女士们好
Hey, ladies.
很不错的组合动作
It was a great combination.
打得不错 李
Great fight, Lee.
比赛时要集中注意力 老兄
Fought with a lot of heart, man.
我亲爱的斗士还好吗
How's my favorite gladiator?
早上好 指挥官
Good morning, Commander.
准备好回舰了?
Ready to go back to our ship?
嗨 如果你打完了 我们安排个私人活动如何
Hey, if you're done brawling, how about we arrange a private tussle?
我还有一场要打
Well, actually I have another bout.
上校
Colonel.
今晚怎样?
How's it going tonight?
拳赛很精彩
Couple of good bouts so far.
你呢 你感觉如何
And you? How're you doing?
我宁愿回到我的小窝里抱着老酒过
I'd rather go back to my rock and crawl under the covers with a bottle,
不过你是对的 这是个好主意
but you were right, this was a good idea.
不必困扰于过去 适应明亮的灯光下的生活
No use going backwards, might as well get used to the bright lights.
开始了 开始了
Let's go. Let's go!
你在这儿
There you are.
嗨 你好吗
Hey, how are you?
没想到找到你的时候是在玩沙子
I didn't expect to find you playing in the sand.
那不是沙子
It's not sand.
那是冲积物 这里过去是河床
It's alluvial deposits. This used to be the river mouth.
那你得把鞋子脱下
And you just had to take off your shoes
才能在冲积物上玩
and play in the alluvial deposits.
多浪漫啊!
How romantic.
你衣服颜色真不错
That's a nice color on you.
谢谢
Thank you.
很高兴见到你  劳拉
It's good to see you, Laura.
我也是  比尔
You, too, Bill.
什么
What?
没什么
Nothing.
我父亲是个搏击迷呢
My father was an avid fight fan.
我很崇拜父亲  所以我也喜欢看精彩的搏击
I adored my father so I love a good fight.
我听说了你所谓的舞会了
I heard about your so-called dance.
是偶然听到的
Accidentally, I might add.
不是私人舞会
Don't take it personally.
这是士兵的传统
It's sort of a private tradition.
传统?
Tradition?
因为老是在军舰上待着会让人沮丧
There's a lot of frustration aboard warships.
争论会带来不合还会演化成仇恨
Arguments become grudges and end up being feuds.
这种形式可以让他们合理地释放压力
It allows them to let off some steam,
以公开的形式  大家都能参与
out in the open so everybody can participate.
不管是什么军衔 只要你把身份牌丢进箱子里
Rank doesn't matter. As long as you throw your tags in the box,
都能参加一个公平的比赛
everyone's fair game.
你把身份牌扔进去了没有?
Did you throw your tags in there?
没有
No.
不 其实我想丢的
No. I wish,
我面对了太多压力
with all the frustrations that I have.
我得提前祝贺你
Congratulations. I may be jumping the gun,
在卡拉狄加上出生的第一个男孩
but first boy born on Galactica.
我就是为这事来找您的 长官
That's the thing I wanted to talk to you about, sir.
凯莉不想孩子出生在这里
Cally doesn't want him born here.
我也不想 毕竟他…
And neither do I. Not if he has a chance
有机会呼吸着新鲜的空气出生
to grow up breathing fresh air.
你要说什么
What are you saying?
谢谢
Thank you.
请允许让我们离开这里的岗位
Well, we both would like to request to be relieved of duty
去新卡布里卡定居
and resettle in New Caprica.
不行
No. No way.
这期间你们得呆在这里
Look, you're both here for the duration.
下一个出场的是热狗!
Next up is Hotdog.
热狗  把你的屁股挪上来  然后选个对手
Hotdog, get your butt up here and pick a partner.
来吧 冠军
Come on there, champ.
谁是你的对手呢  热狗?
TIGH: Who's your partner, Hotdog?
星芭
Starbuck.
你一定是在开玩笑？
You gotta be kidding, right?
上  星芭!  他是你的了
Go, Starbuck. He's yours.
我六岁的时候 我家隔壁有个男孩
When I was six years old, there was this boy in my neighborhood,
他每天都等我放学后把我推倒
he used to wait for me after school and knock me down.
知道我妈妈怎么说吗
Know what my mom told me?
那不是因为我惹怒了他
It wasn't because I pissed him off.
后来我终于明白
I wasn't too much older when I realized
恨的另外一面是爱
that the other side of hatred is love.
这就是情感
It was passion.
这次卡尔对李充满了怒火
Karl is angry at Lee after all this time.
这究竟是为何而战呢?
What is this fight really about?
干得好
That's it.
来吧 来吧
TIGH: Come on. Come on!
她只是要激怒我 就这么简单
She's just been pissing me the frak off, that's all.
现在她要丢下拳套了
Now she's throwing down the gauntlet.
打得好 就该这么打
That's it. That's the way to fight! Go, go, go.
我不敢相信他们的进度这么快
Can't believe the progress they've made.
一个月以前跟现在完全不一样
You should've seen it a month ago.
嗯  相比这种到处都是垃圾的地方
But I'd still rather sleep in a warm bunk every night
我情愿每晚睡在暖和的军舰铺位上
than muck around in this muck.
今晚的床位会很暖和的
Bunk's gonna be plenty warm tonight.
他同意了
He said yes.
他批准你调职了?
He approved the transfer?
恩
Yeah.
你俩就不会保守点秘密  对吗?
STARBUCK: You two just don't know how to keep a secret, do you?
你们是不是准备和波塔尔一起扛起铁铲呢?
So, what, are you guys here to see Baltar put a shovel in the ground?
"参加我们建设美好明天的庆典"
"Join the celebration as we break ground for a better tomorrow. "
噢  有那么多的废话
Aw, such a load of crap.
会有一个露天酒吧
There's an open bar.
真的吗?  那你们干嘛不参加呢?
Really? See, now why didn't you say so?
李  你最好也表表态
Lee, you've got to let your better half do the talking for you.
她刚才说到点子上了
She gets right to the point.
让我们去见识下美好的"新明天"吧
Let's go find us a better tomorrow.
我们先走了
Excuse us.
把自己灌醉吧
Knock yourself out.
谢谢 山姆
Thank you, Sam.
谢谢大家
Thank you. Thank you.
让我们记住这一天 作为我们
Let this day be remembered as the day that we broke the ground
新的明天的奠基日
for our new tomorrow.
你拉链开了
Your fly's open.
闭嘴
Shut up.
不  一切都会好起来的  对不对?
No, it gets better, okay?
因为到时候他们都会回衣帽间的
They come back to the locker room
会带上手铐  还有两根稻草杆!
with a set of handcuffs and some straw.
他们不会成为朋友的 对吗
They're not gonna be friends, are they?
我一直都想和一个球员约会
You know, I've always wanted to date a ballplayer.
有力的臂弯..
Such great arms.
我猜他有对象了
Guess he's kind of taken now.
是啊 有了
Yeah. Kind of.
这里的天气经常很恶劣
Weather usually sucks down here anyway.
是啊
Yeah.
我在想 或许…
You know, I was thinking it's probably better
还是在卡拉狄加上生小孩更好吧
to have a baby on Galactica anyways.
那里有医务室、医生、药品
You know, there's a sick bay, doctors, medicine.
不  这里会更好
Yeah. No, it'll be better.
我们也会更开心的
Yeah, we'll be happier.
没错
Yeah.
嗨 宝贝 你好啊
Hey, baby. Hi.
我听说山姆上船了
I heard Sam was aboard.
是吗
He was?
运气不错 他现在又走了
With any luck, he's gone now.
怎么回事
What happened?
同样的事总是会发生
Same thing that always happens.
为什么他们不能让事情简单些
Why can't they just make things simple?
他们都认为你该属于他们…
They start thinking that they own you...
他们? 我们在说谁?
They? Which they are we talking about?
山姆还是李
Sam or Lee?
我不想你和她打
I don't want you to fight her.
小杜 我和她之间没什么
Dee, this has nothing to do with us.
卡拉和我 我们要解决些东西
Kara and I, we got a score we gotta settle.
我们会在今晚以这种方式解决
And we're gonna settle it tonight one way or another.
喊下一组来
MAN: Set! Call the next set.
好 谁是下一个
WOMAN: Okay, who's next?
嗨 来啊
Hey, come here.
你看我的眼神怪怪的
You keep giving me these weird looks.
得了 一个男人不能看他老婆吗?
Come on, can't a man look at his wife?
来啊
Come on.
在哪?
Where?
我有没有告诉你能和你结婚时我又多高兴
Did I ever tell you how glad I am I married you?
不只一次
Not once.
那好  我要搞个特殊的仪式来纪念一下
Well, then I'll save it for a special occasion.
过来
Come here.
他又犯了他初识我时犯的同样错误
He's been making the same mistake since the day he met me.
那时你和扎克在一起?
When you were with Zak?
对 现在我和山姆在一起
Yeah. And now I'm with Sam.
我不知道干嘛要和你说这些
I don't even know why I'm telling you this.
因为人们说忏悔对灵魂有益
'Cause they say confession's good for the soul.
好  好
Yeah! Yeah.
我来告诉你避免烂醉如泥的秘诀
I'll tell you the secret to avoid hangovers.
那就是一直喝 别停下来
Don't stop drinking.
这是战斗 生存本能在起作用
It's combat. Survival instinct starts to kick in.
作出抉择 不要回头看
Make your choice, don't look back.
漂亮的组合拳
That's a beautiful combination.
我错过了什么?
What did I miss?
菲戈斯基  你把战机修好了吗?
Figurski, you done that bird already?
没呢  是回转仪的麻烦
No, the damn gyro's giving me trouble.
拜托了  军士长  我是唯一还在那边的人
Come on, Chief, I'm the only one over there.
妈的!  自己去找点东西喝吧
Frak. Frak it, get yourself a drink.
船要沉啦  军士长?
Ship down, Chief?
对啊  明天再说了
Yeah, we'll get it tomorrow.
也该让他放松下了
I figured I'd give him a little R&R.
不 别抓绳子 别抓绳子
No! Get off the ropes, get off the ropes!
这是个舞会 记得吗?
It's a dance, remember?
没错 我们是需要了挫折
Yeah, you know, we've had our share of set-backs, to be sure,
但我保证只要我们的新建设计划得以实行
but I'm confident that with our new development plan
我们将拥有能够
we should have the infrastructure to be able
应对任何突发事件的基本设施
to deal with any unforeseen circumstances...
抱歉 长官 财政部长刚走过去 我就来
Excuse me, sir. The finance minister. I'll be back.
去吧
Go ahead.
噢  天啊  我想他都没离开休息过
Oh, my God. I thought he'd never leave.
他是个好小子
He's a good kid.
你说这种东西是当地产的吗?
You're saying this stuff grows around here?
在北面的山上  那儿有一个溪流
In the mountains north of here, there's this little stream
流到这个湖里
that comes down into this lake.
水非常清澈 像玻璃般的清透
The water's so clear, it's like looking through glass.
我想在那边建个小木屋
I'm thinking of building a cabin.
想法不错
It's good.
嗯
Mmm.
是不错
It is good.
嗨 走了
MAN: Hey, get out there.
拜托
WOMAN: Come on.
不 不行    拜托
MAN: No, I don't think so. WOMAN: Come on.
不 不
MAN: No, no, no.
好了 我得走了
Okay, I'm out of here.
什么?    是的
What? Yeah.
拜托 这才刚刚开始热身
Come on, things are just getting warmed up.
我知道
I know, exactly.
来吧 跳舞
Come on, dance.
你吸引了很多目光哦
Look, you're catching more than a few looks,
帕伽索斯的指挥官先生
Mr. Commander of the Pegasus.
嗨 知道吗 别理他们
Hey. You know what? Screw them.
嗨 我们已经保持这个秘密那么久了 别让人知道
Hey, we've kept this under wraps so far, okay? Let's not blow it.
特别是在我要调职之前
Anyway, especially not before I'm about to transfer.
我走了 你留下吧
I'll go. You stay.
没有你 我不会留下来的
I'm not staying without you.
你会的    我不会
Yes, you are. No, I'm not.
Yes, you are. No. I'm not.
我从没过你这么高兴的样子
I've never seen you this happy.
从没见过
I haven't seen you this happy ever.
你呆在这儿 喝个天昏地暗
You stay right here, you get drunk out of your mind,
明天你会烂醉如泥
and tomorrow you'll have a giant hangover.
明晚 我会一个人向我的指挥官报道
Tomorrow night I'll come and make it all better
然后一切都会好起来的
when I report to my new commander, in private.
你能说服我的
You can talk me into it.
在殖民一号上 我厌倦了…
Back on Colonial One I grew so tired
透过窗户看星空
of looking at the stars through the window.
现在 晚上我到外面看啊看
Now at night I go outside and stare and stare.
在破晓前看到一丝光亮
Ever see a little light Before the dawn of the light
和一个女人在溪流边
Got a woman by a stream
要把我所有的梦给她看
Gonna show her all my dreams
这是什么东西?
What the hell is that?
一个飞行员朋友总是在座舱里唱这个
A pilot friend of mine used to sing it in the cockpit all the time.
他叫什么名字    胡安
What was his name? Juan.
胡安 很不错
Juan. That's nice.
胡安 加尔文
Juan Calvin.
是真的吗  比尔?
Is this really it, Bill?
我们要在这里这样度过余生吗?
Is this how we're going to spend all the rest of our days?
啊 你这个男人
Yeah. You the man.
你能帮我拿着吗?  谢谢
Can you hold these? Thank you.
军士长
Chief.
把你那又肥又大的屁股挪上来
Get your fat, lazy ass up here.
他是认真的吗
Is he serious?
我们看着瞧
Let's watch and find out.
西洛
Helo.
绑紧点
Make them tight.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
他是个老头了 没事的
He's an old man. It'll be fine.
再说  他也不是认真的
He's not serious anyways.
真想打吗?
Sure about this?
是你要倒霉了
It's your funeral.
加油!  伙计
MAN: Yeah! Do it, buddy.
起来  军士长  我们才刚开始呢
Get up, Chief. We're just getting started.
加油  军士长
Come on, Chief.
我带来更多的
I bring offerings.
真是时候 我喝的可是烈酒
Just in time. I was running on bingo fuel.
喔  看看那里
Wow, look at that.
你都把安德斯喝到桌底下去了
You literally drank Anders under the table.
他们和平时判若两人 是吗?
They just don't make them like they used to, do they?
小杜在哪?
Where's Dee?
她正在打包 准备走了
She packed it in to go pack.
那只剩下我们俩了
Guess it's just you and me then.
是啊  就剩下我们俩了
Yup, it's just you and me.
你就是这样对付敌人的吗  军士长?
Is this how you fight your enemies, Chief?
你就是这样为生活奋斗的?
Is this how you fight for your life?
别找借口 让我看看你像个战士的样子 起来!
No excuses. Show me you're a soldier. Get up.
给他看看你的厉害
MAN: Show him to your fullest.
对了 军士长 给他看看
That's it, Chief. Show him.
加油
Come on!
这就是你想要的吗?  这就是你想要的吗?
Is that what you want? Is that what you wanted?
知道吗
You know,
也许我们就这样享受就行了
maybe we should just enjoy this.
是的
I am.
不 不 我是指享受在这里的生活
No, no, I mean, enjoy being here
在这个星球上 能多久就多久
on this planet as long as it lasts.
也许赛昂人会找到我们  也许它们找不到
I mean, maybe the Cylons come back, maybe they don't.
但是现在我们要休息一下
But for now, right now, we've got a break.
或许我们该拥抱这些
Maybe we should embrace it,
珍惜现在拥有的生活
live the life that we've got while we've got it.
拥抱这个世界 这样的生活
And embrace this world and this life
看看未来会如何
and see what that brings us.
我手下好多人想从战舰上下来 定居在这里
I've got people that want to get off the ship, move down here.
也不能责怪他们 你会怎么做?
Can't say as I blame them, I mean, what are you gonna do?
让他们象囚犯一样困在上面
You gonna keep them up there like prisoners,
没日没夜重复枯燥的工作
running around in circles all night, all day,
等待末日启示?
waiting for the apocalypse?
哦 末日启示已经来临过了
Well, the apocalypse has happened once before.
对
Yeah.
而你无法阻止这一切发生 比尔 无论是过去还是现在
And there was nothing you could do to stop it, Bill, not then, not now.
面对现实吧
I mean, let's get real. Let's get real.
赛昂人回来 我们会死
The Cylons come back, we're dead.
生了重病 我们会死
Disease strikes, we're dead.
地震 火山 飓风
Earthquake, volcano, hurricane,
今天 明天 也许在五年后…
today, tomorrow, five years from now and it's...
你知道我说什么吧?
And you know what I'd say?
生活是个婊子 人总要死
Life's a bitch and then you die.
你知道…  不 我是认真的
You know... No, no, I'm serious.
我想…
I mean, I think that...
我们应该从现在起 把每天每刻
I think we should all look at every moment
都看成是借来的时间
of every day from now on as borrowed time,
人们该过上
and people should live the lives
他们所期望的生活 直到终点
that they want to live before it's over.
我们就别浪费我们拥有的那点时间
Let's stop spending the little time we have left here
来担心末日何时来临了
worrying about when it's gonna end.
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
看看 这块地方很适合盖间房子
Check it out. It's a great place for a house.
你真的决定不再飞了吗?
So, you're really gonna give up flying?
现在即使继续飞也没什么意思
Flying's gonna suck now anyway.
全都是没完没了的警戒巡逻
Lots of training, endless caps.
战争已经结束了 连同所有有意义的东西
War is over. So is all the good stuff.
别这么说 这不吉利
No, don't say that. You'll jinx it.
嗯
Mmm.
我现在站的位置是什么 厨房吗?
So, what am I standing in now? Is this the kitchen?
嗯
Mmm.
是卧室
Bedroom.
不 不 不 不 谢谢你了 这不是我想来的地方
No. No, no, no. No thank you. That is not someplace I wanna go,
压根就不想 好吗
or think about or imagine or anything else, okay.
看来是我一厢情愿了
That sounds like a personal problem to me.
就是带我来参观你的房子 是吗
Just give me a tour of your house, okay?
给我看你和你的金字塔男孩未来的漂亮房间
Show me all the great rooms you and Pyramid-Boy are gonna have,
多棒的装饰 还有很酷的家具
all the great views, all the cool furniture.
给我介绍一下卡拉・安德斯未来的幸福生活
Give me a tour of the future life of Kara Anders.
我不会结婚的
I'm not getting married.
那么你所做的又都是为了什么呢  卡拉?
Well, then, what's the point, Kara?
我意思是  你确实爱他  对吧？
I mean, you love him, right?
为什么提这个  李?
Where are we going with this, Lee?
这就是问题所在  难道不是吗？
Well, now that's the question, isn't it?
我们到底要怎样下去?
Where are we going?
我的意思是  如果就这样了
I mean, what if this is it?
卡拉  你的余生
This, the rest of your life, Kara.
这真的是你想过的生活吗?
Is this how you want to spend it?
谁是你想相伴余生的人?
Who you want to spend it with?
你心里有某个人吗 李?
You got someone in mind, Lee?
告诉我你不害怕 我不会来
Tell me you're not afraid that I'm not gonna come along
干扰你计划好的未来
and upset your neat little applecart.
或许我希望被干扰
Maybe I want it upset.
看来这下子事情更不好处理了
Well, that makes things more complicated.
是啊
Yeah.
我们该怎么办?
What are we gonna do?
我们接受事实
We accept it.
明天我去和杜说  你去告诉山姆
Tomorrow I tell Dee, you tell Sam.
就那样做吗?
Just like that?
就是那样
Just like that.
我不知道
I don't know.
听着  我们告诉他们我们的感受
You know, we tell them how we feel.
我们把想法都冲天喊出来
We shout it to the skies.
是嘛
Yeah.
是啊  是啊  对
Yeah. Yeah, right.
什么  你不相信我会那样做吗?
What, you don't think I will?
嗯
Mmm-mmm.
李！
Lee!
我是李・阿达玛
My name is Lee Adama!
我爱卡拉・瑟瑞丝!
And I love Kara Thrace!
别太激动啦
Come down.
呵呵  又不会有人听到
What? What, it's not like anybody will hear,
我们在你的森林小木屋里  不是吗？
we're in your cabin in the forest, right?
我爱卡拉・瑟瑞丝
I love Kara Thrace!
不管谁他妈的知道我都不在乎!
And I don't care who frakking knows!
噢  你疯了 过来躺下
Oh, you're crazy. Get down.
来吧  除非你也站起来喊
Well, come on. I'm not going to stop
否则我不会停下的
until you get up and do it, too.
我办不到
I can't.
这是卡拉・瑟瑞丝 赛昂突袭机杀手 她会害怕?
This is Kara Thrace, scourge of the Cylon Raiders. She's afraid?
来吧 起来
Come on, stand up.
不
No.
我会...好吧  再来一次
I'm gonna... Okay, here we go again.
李・阿达玛
Lee Adama...
好了好了
Okay, okay, okay. Okay.
好
Okay.
卡...
Ka...
卡拉・瑟瑞丝爱李・阿达玛!
Kara Thrace loves Lee Adama!
你确信我是你想要的人?
Are you sure I'm what you want?
没错 你就是
Yeah, you're what I want.
我只是…一直没有意识到这一点
I just don't... I don't think I really knew it
直到我刚才大声说出口
until I said it out loud just now.
为什么
Why?
因为扎克?
Because of Zak?
是吧 还有好多其他事
Yeah, and a lot of things.
最主要是我害怕
Mostly because I was afraid
承认多么需要你
to admit how much I needed you.
我有多么需要你
How much I needed anyone.
对
Yeah.
我爱你 卡拉・瑟瑞丝
I love you, Kara Thrace.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
加油
Come on!
老头子打得不错
The old man's got chops.
他知道什么时候进攻 什么时候防守
He knows when to make his moves, when to hold back.
我真希望他儿子也学学他
I wish I could say the same for his son.
你们为什么还要上台打?
Why are you two even fighting?
为什么不直接去开个房?
Why not just get a room?
在那 做那个
Been there, done that.
估计我们都觉得搞错方式了
Guess it just rubbed us both the wrong way.
小杜
Dee,
她说的都是以前的事
what she's talking about was a long time ago.
老早以前的 说明不了什么
A long time ago. It didn't mean anything.
你说你要解决些问题
You said you had something to settle.
去解决吧
Settle it.
就今晚
Tonight.
听我说啊…
Listen to me. Listen.
又只剩我们两个了
And once again, it's just you and me.
你他妈的
You motherfrakker!
别这么想 好吗
Hold that thought, okay?
老爸  加油!
Come on, Dad!
不太好  已经够了  你该认输了
That's bad. That's enough already. You should quit.
把血止上就行了
Just stop the blood.
拿止血剂来消肿止血
Coagulant for the swelling as for the bleeding.
拜托 天啊
Come on. Christ.
你还要坚持吗
You insist on doing this?
你还要打  你疯了吗?
You wanna do this, you're crazy, right?
你真想继续打吗?      是的
You wanna do this? Yeah.
那好  你要防守好  他要发狠了
All right. Keep your guard up, he's coming in wild,
你要用左勾拳还击 你想要赢吗?
get him with a left hook. You wanna win?
我赢不了的
I'm not gonna win.
当心他的直拳
You gotta watch his jab. Watch his jab.
他的直拳太狠了  听到了吗?
His jab's killing you, all right?
睁大你的眼睛看好
Just keep your eyes open.
好 准备上了
All right, here you go. Have some. Open up.
你看上去很好
Okay, you're looking good.
保持体力 小心直拳 上吧
Keep strong, watch his jab. Here we go.
嗨
Hey.
醒醒 给
Wake up. Here.
要咖啡吗?
Want some coffee?
能让你舒服点 相信我
You'll feel better, trust me.
军士长  早上好  早上好  凯莉
Chief, good morning. Good morning, Kelly.
我仔细考虑了你说的话 或许你是对的
I've been thinking about what you said, and you may be right,
关于你的话…
about what you said.
不好意思 什么?
I'm sorry, what?
哦 好吧
Oh, right.
关于要下来定居的事
About living down here.
一艘太空堡垒没地方养个家庭
A Battlestar's no place to raise a family.
我会想念你的  军士长
So I'm gonna miss you, Chief.
祝你好运
But I'm gonna wish you good luck.
谢谢你  长官
Thank you, sir.
衷心祝福你们
My best to both of you.
我们可以搬家了?  真的吗?
We're moving? Really?
谢谢你
Thank you.
我希望你俩将来至少生一打
I want you guys to have at least a dozen.
你会看到的
We'll see about that.
起来 我们帮你
Get up. We'll get you up.
当你们站在这个甲板上 你们就要作好战斗的准备
When you stand on this deck, you be ready to fight,
否则你就是质疑我们在里的原因
or you dishonor the reason why we're here.
请记住
And remember this.
当你在和某人战斗时  他就不再是你的朋友
When you fight a man, he's not your friend.
当你们领导别人的时候  也是一样的
The same goes when you lead men.
我曾经忽略过一次
I forgot that once.
我让你们都走得太近了 所有的人
I let you get too close. All of you.
我放松了自己的警惕
I dropped my guard.
我让这个团队 这个大家庭几乎分崩瓦解
I let this crew, and this family, disband.
我们为此付出了生命的代价
And we paid the price in lives.
我不会让这种事情再发生了
That can't happen again.
菲戈斯基 你跟我来
Figurski, you're with me.
让我们去把那架战机修好
Let's get that bird back on the line.
总统女士
Madam President.
上将
Admiral.
好了  这次"舞会"就此结束
All right. This dance is over.
带上你们的酒瓶 身份牌  都散了
Get your booze and your dog tags and let's get out of here.
怎么  你就这样结束了?
So what, you're just gonna call it?
今晚你还不够兴奋吗  上尉?
Not enough excitement for one night for you, Captain?
嗨 嗨
STARBUCK: Hey. Hey!
你他妈的想躲哪去?
Where the frak do you think you're going?
结束了  卡拉
It's over, Kara.
那又怎么样?
So what?
你有胆量勾搭另一个男人的女人
You have the guts to try and frak
却不敢和一个女人在拳台上较量？
another man's woman, but not to fight one?
小杜是否知道她的男人是个什么样的孬种
I wonder if Dee knew what she was getting.
觉得她会顺从这样的男人吗？
Think she would have settled for sloppy seconds?
真相很伤人  不是吗?
The truth stings, don't it?
你想较量一下吗  上尉？
You want a fight, Captain?
如你所愿
You've got it.
你男朋友在呼呼大睡
Your boyfriend snores.
我来告诉你避免烂醉如泥的秘诀
I'll tell you the secret to avoid hangovers.
那就是一直喝 别停下来
Don't stop drinking.
这是你第一次和我一起喝酒
Well, I think that is the first drink you've
卡拉・瑟瑞丝上尉
ever had with me, Captain Kara Thrace.
肯定有什么特别的事
Must be a special occasion.
我昨晚和李睡了
I slept with Lee last night.
你能别笑了吗 这不好玩
Would you stop it? It's not funny.
不好玩
It's not!
我是个白痴
I'm such an idiot.
是你说的 我没这么说
Well, you said it, I didn't.
嗨
Hey.
干嘛不和我说说整件事
Why don't you tell me all about it?
我得选条路
I gotta make a move.
二择其一
One way or the other.
这是战斗
It's combat.
生存本能在起作用
Survival instinct starts to kick in.
作出抉择 不要回头看
Make your choice, don't look back.
生存本能 嗯?
Survival instinct, huh?
是
Yeah.
早上好 指挥官 准备回舰了吗
Good morning, Commander. Ready to go back to our ship?
就这样保守秘密啊
So much for keeping a lid on things.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们离开这鬼地方吧
Let's get the hell out of here.
怎么 怕打到我
What? You afraid to hit me?
还是根本打不到?
Or maybe you can't.
起来 星芭 起来 你能行的
Get up! Starbuck, get up! You can do this.
早上好  上将
Good morning, Admiral.
你看上去精神不错啊
You look like you had a good time.
是啊  参加了几个派对
Yeah, it was some party.
噢  这个早上也不寻常啊
Yeah, well, it's been a hell of a morning, too.
你错过了精彩的部分
You missed all the excitement.
为什么?  上面出了什么问题吗？
Why? Is it problems upstairs?
不
No.
不 是好事情 卡拉结婚了
No, good things. Kara got married.
相信吗?
You believe that?
什么?
What?
嗯  大概一个小时之前
Yeah, about an hour ago.
她自己找了个牧师 婚礼在河边举行的
Found herself a priest, went down by the river and got married.
你没事吧?
You okay?
你能相信吗?
ADAMA: Can you believe that?
她理应得到他
Well, she deserves that man.
我们都应该得到幸福
We all deserve to be happy.
我已经同意她离开舰队 跟泰罗尔和凯莉一起
I also gave her permission to muster out, along with Tyrol and Cally.
还有其他几个人  所以…
A few of the others, so...
我们得确保没有大规模的离职
We have to ask to make sure there's no mass exodus.
嘿  伙计!你听到消息了吗?
Hey, man. Did you hear the news?
我们结婚了 我们结婚了!
We're hitched. We got married.
你能相信吗?
Can you believe it?
不  不  我无法相信
No. No, I can't believe it.
是啊 太不可思议了 她过来我这儿  把我叫醒
Yeah. You know, it was crazy. She comes down and she wakes me up,
突然提出结婚  然后把我拽到牧师那里
she pops the question, she drags me down to the priest,
然后  哇  一眨眼间  我们结婚了
and bang! Like that. We're married.
这么说是你的主意
So it was your idea.
没错 是我的主意
Yeah. It was my idea.
你俩是不是需要点时间单独聊聊
SAM: Do you guys want a minute to, you know, talk?
祝贺你  山姆
Congratulations, Sam.
谢谢
Yeah.
祝好运
And good luck.
你们需要这个
You're gonna need it.
怎么 我犯规了?
Oops. Did I break the rules?
你只做了一件事 不惜一切保护自己
You've only got one. Protect yourself at all costs.
你从不让人进去心扉
You never let anybody get inside.
我作出了选择
I made my choice.
你跑开了
You ran away.
加油 姑娘 你能打到他!
WOMAN: Let's go, girl. You can take him!
真相很伤人 不是吗
The truth stings, don't it?
你这个伪君子 你做了什么选择呢?
You frakking hypocrite. What choice did you make?
怎么了
What's going on?
这是在干嘛
What's it look like?
看上去他们想杀了对方
Looks like they're trying to kill each other.
从某个角度来看
From one perspective.
到底怎么回事
Where is this coming from?
我不知道 我也在想
I don't know. I've been thinking about it for a while.
不 这是谎话
No, that's a lie.
我不想用谎话作为开局
And I don't wanna start this with a lie.
卡拉和安德斯早上结婚了
Kara and Anders got married this morning.
怎么? 他们结婚有什么特别的？
And what, they're having a two-for-one special?
当卡拉说她结婚了的时候 我就在想
When Kara said she was married, it really made me think
我想要过什么样的生活
about the life I wanna live now.
我希望和你在一起
And I want you in that life.
和你在一起度过的日子
The times we've been together,
是我这生中最快乐的日子
they're the happiest I've ever been. Ever.
小杜 嫁给我好吗
So, please, Dee, will you marry me?
你是不是忘了什么
Aren't you forgetting something?
你爱卡拉・瑟瑞丝
You love Kara Thrace.
什么 不
What? No.
你们之间有某种关系
The two of you were linked somehow,
我是说 会有一天 你会来跟我说
and I mean, one day, you're gonna turn to me and say,
“小杜 我很抱歉 可是...”   不会的
"Dee, I'm sorry, but... " That's not gonna happen.
会的    不会
It will happen. No.
但是好吧
And yes,
我会嫁给你的
I'll marry you.
你同意了?
You will?
我也在想
I've been thinking, too.
或许我们现在是安全的 可谁知道能持续多久呢
Maybe we're safe, but who knows for how long?
我要把每一天都当作最后一天来过
I wanna live my life like every moment is gonna be my last.
我甚至会嫁给你 李・阿达玛
I'll even marry you, Lee Adama.
我会爱你 珍惜你
And I will love you and cherish you
直到赛昂人来
until the Cylons come back,
或者到卡拉・瑟瑞丝走进你的生活
or until Kara Thrace walks back into your life.
小杜 她不会回来
Dee, she's not walking back.
我是说…
I mean...
吻我
Just kiss me.
在我改变主意前吻我
Kiss me before I change my mind.
加油    打啊 姑娘
MAN: Let's go! MAN 2: Fight, girl!
加油
Let's go!
加油 李 教训她
Come on, Lee, kick her ass!
对
Yeah.
好啊
Yeah!
你想了解一切?
You're trying to finish things?
把他放倒 宝贝
Put him down, baby.
加油
Come on.
放开我
Let go of me.
为什么 好让你多打我几下?
Why? So that you can hit me some more?
对
Yeah.
好吧 我可能走都走不了了
Well, I may not be able to walk anymore.
你打破了我的鼻子
I think you busted my nose.
我们算是打平了 怎么样?
How about we call this a tie, huh?
我出去了
I'm out of here.
我想你
I missed you.
我也想你
I missed you, too.
看来事情又变复杂了
I think things just got more complicated.
别 别 别现在
No, no, not now.